Guide to the
Brown University Library
- Draft of Brown, Nicholas to Rusconi, Carlo Rome, Italy, 1849 February 18; 2 pages; Brown, Nicholas, 1792-1859 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page 109)
  Draft of letter—eventually dated February 18, 1849—in which Brown assures Rusconi, the foreign affairs minister of the Roman Republic, that the government of the United States will recognize the Roman Republic at the nearest opportune moment. Brown goes on to express his enthusiasm for the Roman Republic, praising in particular the calm that its government has been able to maintain despite turbulent circumstances and speaking of a new "modern Rome" that follows in the legacy of the great men of its storied past. See also: bdr710156.
  Ms 660
- Mazzini, Giuseppe to Brown, Nicholas Rome, Italy, 1849 June 14; 1 page; Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1805-1872 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page 110)
  Informs Brown that room has been reserved at the Albani Palace to give shelter to certain "American ladies and gentlemen" about whom Brown had previously written to Mazzini. Mazzini assures Brown that there is no danger of a particularly serious bombardment. Postscript reflects more generally on the military and political situation currently facing Rome: "We cannot ask any body to mediate. We are right and have no fear. Let God and our army help Rome."
  Ms 661
- Mazzini, Giuseppe to Brown, Nicholas Rome, Italy, 1849 July 5; 1 page; Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1805-1872 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page 111)
  Asks that Brown help three young men obtain passports, as Mazzini knows the men well. Two of the men are Bianchi Piolti and Leone Fortis; the third name is illegible.
  Ms 662
  Brown, Nicholas, 1792-1859; Fortis, Leone, 1824-1896; Piolti, Bianchi
- Mazzini, Giuseppe to Brown, Nicholas Rome, Italy, 1849; 1 page; Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1805-1872 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page 111)
  "I must be off; so, I leave the lines you gave to me and the translation. Tomorrow you will have the introductory letters for Mrs. Brown. Be so good as to read the little pamphlet I send. I am sure you will like it."
  Ms 663
  Brown, Nicholas, 1792-1859; Brown, Caroline Matilda Clements
- Niccolini, G.B. to Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1 page; Niccolini, G.B. (Giovanni Battista), 1782-1861 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page 112)
  Niccolini had previously asked Mazzini to send him a surgeon to work on his right hand, which had been injured. A surgeon is no longer needed, since Niccolini has been able to find a good one himself.
  Ms 664
- Garibaldi, Giuseppe to Pastacaldi, Michele London, England, 1854 February 22; 1 page; Garibaldi, Giuseppe, 1807-1882 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page 112)
  Regards the success of Garibaldi's fundraising efforts in the United States,. Also discusses a shipment of coal that Garibaldi is arranging between Geneva and Newcastle.
  Ms 665
  Pastacaldi, Michele
- Dal Papa al Concilio di Giuseppe Mazzini, 1849 September; 16 pages; Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1805-1872 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page loose in back)
  A printed volume of Mazzini's reflections on the Papacy in Italy. According to the introductory paragraph, the contents of the volume had been written by Mazzini over the course of years since 1832, but he is re-printing them in 1849 at a time when he feels that the "religious question" is newly important to Italy.
- La Reazione e La Democrazia di Giuseppe Mazzini Genoa, Italy, 1830; 16 pages; Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1805-1872 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page loose in back)
  A printed volume containing an essay in which Mazzini writes about the social order, revolution, and contemporary Europe.
- Lettera di Giuseppe Mazzini intorno gli affari di Roma al Sigg. De Tocqueville e De Falloux, Ministri della Repubblica Francese, [1849] September 18; 24 pages; Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1805-1872 (Box 10, Volume 4, Page loose in back)
  A printed volume of a public letter Mazzini writes to the French ministers De Tocqueville and De Falloux, arguing against comments they previously made about Republican efforts in Rome. What emerges is an account of the brief life of the Roman Republic. Front cover bears a stamp of the Ferrante Gonnelli bookstore, address: Via Cavour 50 in Florence.
  Tocqueville, Alexis de, 1805-1859; Falloux du Coudray, Alfred-Frédéric-Pierre, comte de, 1811-1886; Falloux du Coudray, Alfred-Frédéric-Pierre, comte de, 1811-1886
- Ultimi avvenimenti di Roma, 1849; 16 pages; Sterbini, Pietro (Box 10, Volume 4, Page loose in back)
  A printed volume containing an essay written by Pietro Sterbini and originally published in the periodical Contemporaneo regarding republican revolutionary events in Rome in 1849. Divided into three sections: "Storia degli ultimi fatti accaduti in Roma"; "Felici risultati degli ultimi avvenimenti"; and "Appello a tutte le classi dei Cittadini."
  Pius IX, Pope, 1792-1878; Morandi, Giuseppe